Guide to the Walter Jack Cunningham Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Walter Jack Cunningham papers
1941-1987
MS 1479
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.5
(15 boxes)
The papers consist of teaching materials for electrical engineering and engineering and applied sciences courses taught at Yale University. Included are lecture notes, problems, and examinations.
Cunningham, Walter Jack, 1917-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of W. Jack Cunningham, 1988.
Scope and Contents
The Walter Jack Cunningham Papers are composed of course sylabii, lecture notes, problem sets, exams, and other course materials, which document Walter Jack Cunningham's long career teaching engineering. Cunningham gave his papers to the Yale University Library in 1988.
The papers are arranged by course title, and all materials for a course are grouped together. Course titles are listed chronologically according to the earliest date the course was offered and files include all materials used for the same course in following years. When materials were used for more than one course, the materials are filed under the earliest course date, with later course numbers indicated in parentheses in the list that follows.
The earliest papers date from Cunningham's course in acoustics at Harvard University. Subsequent materials relate to courses taught at Yale University in the departments of electrical engineering, engineering and applied science, and mathematics. Cunningham's work at Yale focused on applied math and linear systems theory, and the assembled materials demonstrate the evolution of courses in systems and control and calculus. Other course materials relate to topics in electron optics, engineering analysis, fields and circuits, and energy.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Walter Jack Cunningham was born on August 21, 1917, in Comanche, Texas. He graduated from Waco High School and attended Baylor University, before transferring to the University of Texas. He received his A.B. degree from there in 1937 and his A.M. degree in 1938. Cunningham did further graduate work at Harvard University and received an M.S. in 1939 and a Ph.D. in 1947. While at Harvard he taught in the Physics Department. Cunningham joined the Yale University faculty in 1946 and taught in the departments of electrical engineering, engineering and applied science, and mathematics. His chief areas of research included systems theory, non-linear analysis, computation, and acoustics. He served on the editorial board of American Scientist and is the author of Nonlinear Analysis. Cunningham died in Hamden, Connecticut, on January 7, 2004.
Calculus -- Study and teaching; Electrical engineering -- Study and teaching; System analysis -- Study and teaching; Cunningham, Walter Jack, 1917-; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Dept. of Electrical Engineering; Yale University. Dept. of Engineering and Applied Science
- Inventory
  - Physics 26a--Acoustics, 1941 November 12 - 1946 August (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - Electrical Engineering 33a--Alternating-Current Circuits, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Electrical Engineering 103--Engineering Analysis (EAS 400), 1946-1957 (Box 1, Folder 9-15)
  - Electrical Engineering 103--Engineering Analysis (EAS 400), 1957-1964 (Box 2, Folder 16-23)
  - Electrical Engineering 120a--Acoustics, 1947-1955, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24-27)
  - Electrical Engineering 120a--Acoustics, undated (Box 3, Folder 28-32)
  - Electrical Engineering 117b--Electron Optics, 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 33-35)
  - Electrical Engineering 127b--Nonlinear Analysis (Numerical Analysis) (EAS 424a), 1953-1966 (Box 3, Folder 36-41)
  - Electrical Engineering 127b--Nonlinear Analysis (Numerical Analysis) (EAS 424a), undated (Box 4, Folder 42-44)
  - Electrical Engineering 127a--Numerical Analysis (EAS 57b), 1956-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 45-48)
  - Electrical Engineering 28--Fields and Circuits, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 49-52)
  - Electrical Engineering 28--Fields and Circuits, 1962-1964 (Box 5, Folder 53-57)
  - Electrical Engineering 35--Electronic Circuits (EAS 35a, 29a, 35b), 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 58-60)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 20--Engineering Science, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 61-63)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 12a--Computers, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 64-65)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 12a--Computers, 1967-1972, undated (Box 6, Folder 66-73)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 13b--Communications and Control (EAS 45a), 1967-1973 (Box 6, Folder 74-81)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 84b--Seminar in Environmental Quality Control, 1971-1976 (Box 7, Folder 82-88)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 76a-130a--Control System I (K.S. Narenda), 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 89-92)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 77b--Control Systems (421b), 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 93-97)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 36b--Introduction to Automatic Control (A.S. Morse), 1974 (Box 7, Folder 98-99)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 36a--Systems and Control I, 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 100-104)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 37b--Systems and Control II (337b), 1974-1978 (Box 8, Folder 105-108)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 336a--Systems and Control I, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 109-110)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 336a--Systems and Control I, 1978-1980 (Box 9, Folder 111-112)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 337b--Systems and Control II, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 113-120)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 337--Systems and Control II, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 21a--Applied Math I (CS 27a, EAS 84b, Systems 10, EAS 34c), 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 122-124)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 30b--Applied Math I (195b, 295a), 1975-1983 (Box 10, Folder 125-129)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 295b--Applied Math I (195b), 1978-1982 (Box 11, Folder 130-135)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 33c (Systems 10)--Systems Theory (K.S. Narenda), 1976 (Box 11, Folder 136-138)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 34c, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Systems 20--Applications of Systems Theory, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 140-144)
  - Systems 20--Applications of Systems Theory, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 145-146)
  - Math 120a--Calculus of Functions of Several Variables (B.T. Chu; S. Lang), 1976-1977 (Box 12, Folder 147-149)
  - Math 120a--Calculus of Functions of Several Variables, 1977-1981 (Box 12, Folder 150-156)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 130a--Energy: The Next Thirty Years, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 157)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 109a--Perspectives on Energy, 1979-1981 (Box 13, Folder 158-162)
  - Electrical Engineering 336a--Systems and Control I, 1982-1987 (Box 13, Folder 163-168)
  - Electrical Engineering 337b--Systems and Control II, 1982-1985 (Box 13, Folder 169)
  - Electrical Engineering 337b--Systems and Control II, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 170-172)
  - Math 120b--Calculus of Functions of Several Variables, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 173)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 194b--Ordinary and Partial Differential Equations with Applications, 1984-1985 (Box 14, Folder 174-175)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 395a/512a--Non-Linear Ordinary Differential Equations with Applications, 1985-1986 (Box 14, Folder 176-178)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 395a/512a--Non-Linear Ordinary Differential Equations with Applications, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 180-181)
  - Historical notes on engineering at Yale, 1978-1980 (Box 15, Folder 182)